

# Bjørnar Moe Remmen

# Software developer



A developer with experiences within machine learning and backend development. As a developer I really like the challenge machine learning gives and the ability to be creative. The last year I also completed a course in Parallel Programming covering CUDA, OpenMPI and basic pthread & openmp use.

# **Experience**

#### **Microchip**

Application Engineer • Aug, 2020 - Present

Writing software both for microcontrollers in C and general backend development.

# Capgemini

Data Scientist • Jan, 2019 — Aug, 2020

Worked with a team that specializing in Computer Vision. One of my projects at a startup that used underwater cameras in fish farms was to try to create a program to monitor the health of the fish using Computer Vision.

## **Making Waves**

Data Scientist • Jul, 2017 — Dec, 2018

Worked as a general developer and Data Scientist. Two of the projects including Machine Learning were a Norwegian Chatbot project in python and Proof of Concept testing Computer Vision in Elastic Search.

#### Kodeklubben Trondheim

Instructor - Internship • Jun, 2016 — Jul, 2016

Kodeklubben is a Norwegian initative to teach children coding. This internship was about teaching HTMl, CSS, JavaScript to people from junior high school and high school.

# **Education**

# Norwegian University of Science and Technology - NTNU

Informatics, M.Sc., Artificial Intelligence • 2015 — 2017

# Sør-Trøndelag University COllege - HiST

Computer Science, B.Sc. • 2012 — 2015

# **Projects**

# jazznotes.io

Founder & Primary Developer • 2012 — Present

Jazz Notes is an open source node/ember app that helps you keep track of your music compositions and new ideas.

## **Springfield Community Outreach Group**

Co-Founder & Organizer • 2007 — Present

SCOG is a local monthly meetup in Springfield where we share opportunities to volunteer in the community and organize support for families and neighborhoods in need of assistance that the community can provide.

#### **Skills**

#### **Parallel Progamming**

Took a course in 2020 at NTNU in parallel rogramming that covered CUDA, OpenMPI, OpenMP and Pthreads. Implemented Convolution in OpenMPI and CUDA getting Ideas from the paper Ghost Cell Pattern

# Recognition

# Global Data Science Challenge 2020 - 1st place

Capgemini • 2020

The challenge was to identify sperm whales by their fluke. [https://www.capgemini.com/client-story/using-ai-to-protect-sperm-whales/] (Using AI to protect sperm whales)

#### **Associations**

#### **School Bar**

Volunteer • 2001 — 2010

The School bar is used by both engineers and other diciplines to socialize. Some responsibilities I had were to work behind the bar and checking IDs at the entrance.

# **Additional Links**

• Capgemini Global Datascience Challenge - Using AI to protect sperm whales